# **REYMOND Y. VILLANUEVA**

# **Bachelor of Science in Information Technology**

Luna, La Union | 09060279223 | reymondyv@gmail.com

https://reymondyv.vercel.app

## **ABOUT ME:**

As a skilled web developer, I optimize website performance, functionality, and user experience using tech stacks like React, Ruby on Rails, and PostgreSQL. I'm proficient in React's Context API and Redux, and knowledgeable in JS and TS, HTML, CSS, TailwindCSS, Firebase, and Vite. I'm committed to ongoing learning and exploring frameworks like NextJS, SSG, ISR, and SSR to enhance website development. My expertise, attention to detail, and dedication to best practices make me an asset to any team, and I deliver visually appealing, functional, and user-friendly websites while staying up to date with the latest trends and technologies in the field.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

## **Squadzip**

Junior Web Developer | August, 2022 - Present

- Migrating current company's web application from version 1 to version 2 maintaining best practices and optimized solution
- Optimizing existing business logic to gain performance, clean, and secure code.
- Providing new features based on the client requests and application's improvement.
- Maintaining old and new features of the application.

## Accenture, Inc.

Application Developer (Internship Trainee) | February, 2022 - June, 2022

- · Developed an application through Microsoft Power Apps
- Studied and familiarize with Microsoft Power Tools e.g., Power Automate, Power Apps,
  Sharepoint
- Created diagrams and UI design for the planning and development phase of the project.
- Participated in team collaboration and sprint meetings.

## **SEMINARS:**

#### The Current Threat Landscape: State Sponsored Cyber Wars

Department of Information and Communications Technology - June 2021

## **Cyber Defense Society Conference 2019**

TrendMicro - September 2019

## **EDUCATION:**

#### August 2018 - June 2022 | Saint Louis University - Baguio City

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

## **SKILLS SUMMARY:**

- Migrating company's web application from version 1 to version 2, providing optimized solution and applying best practices using React and Ruby on Rails. Providing new features based on the client requests and application's improvement. Maintain old and new features of the application.
- Very knowledgeable in version control systems and collaborative tools like Gitlab and GitHub. Used variety of database tools PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Firebase
- I build personal projects using different technology trends like NextJS, TailwindCSS, Firebase/Firestore, TypeScript,
- Developed an Asset Management System for my capstone using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PHP, Laravel, Javascript, and MySQL